vfs-uk-in.com 2016-06-02

# UK Visa Information - India - Privacy Policy

#### PRIVACY POLICY

#### Web site Privacy Policy 

This Privacy Policy sets out the data processing practices carried out through the use of the Internet and any other electronic communications networks by VFS Global Services Pvt Ltd (here in after referred to as “VFS Global” or “We”) If you have any requests concerning your personal information or any queries with regard to these practices please contact us at [privacyofficer@vfsglobal.com](mailto:privacyofficer@vfsglobal.com).

#### Information collected

We collect personal information from visitors to this web site through the use of online forms. We also collect information about the transactions you undertake including details of payment cards used.

We collect additional information automatically about your visit to our web site. 

#### Use of personal information 

We process personal information collected via this web site for the purposes of:

  * providing and personalising our services;
  * dealing with your enquiries and requests;
  * processing requests for visa, work permits and travel document applications;
  * tracking application progress; and
  * administering orders and accounts and responding to applicant enquiries;

[We may also use and disclose information in aggregate (so that no individuals are identified) for marketing and strategic development purposes.]

#### Use of cookies

A cookie is a small piece of information sent by a web server to a web browser, which enables the server to collect information from the browser. Find out more about the use of cookies on [http://www.cookiecentral.com.](http://www.cookiecentral.com/)

We use cookies to identify you when you visit this web site and to keep track of your browsing patterns and build up a demographic profile.

Our use of cookies also allows registered users to be presented with a personalised version of the site, carry out transactions and have access to information about their account.

Most browsers allow you to turn off cookies. If you want to know how to do this please look at the help menu on your browser. However, switching off cookies will restrict your use of our web site.

#### Disclosures

We will only disclose personal information to other companies within our group of companies, government bodies, law enforcement agencies and suppliers we engage to process data on our behalf. We may need to disclose information when required by law. We shall disclose information in good-faith when it is necessary to comply with a court order, any ongoing judicial proceeding, or other legal process served on VFS Global or to exercise the legal rights or defend against legal claims. We may also disclose the information if the disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce our terms and conditions. Further, in any event of a merger, or sale or re-structuring, We may transfer or assign any and all personal information to the appropriate party.

#### Right to opt out 

We respect your privacy and give you an option not to provide information or data that needs to be submitted. You can withdraw your consent that was given to VFS Global earlier. However, the same needs be communicated to VFS Global in writing.

#### Authenticity

We shall not be held responsible for the authenticity or accuracy of the information provided by you. It shall be your duty to ensure that the information provided to VFS Global is accurate.

#### Other web sites

Our web site may contain links to other web sites which are outside our control and are not covered by this Privacy Policy. If you access other sites using the links provided, the operators of these sites may collect information from you which will be used by them in accordance with their privacy policy, which may differ from ours. Neither VFS Global, nor their officers, employees and agents shall have any responsibility or liability of any nature whatsoever for these other websites or any information contained in them, none of which have been verified or endorsed by VFS Global or affiliates.

#### Access right

You have a right to access the personal data held about you. To obtain a copy of the personal information we hold about you, please write to us at [privacyofficer@vfsglobal.com](mailto:privacyofficer@vfsglobal.com).

#### Internet-based transfers

Given that the Internet is a global environment, using the Internet to collect and process personal data necessarily involves the transmission of data on an international basis. Therefore, by browsing this web site and communicating electronically with us, you acknowledge and agree to our processing of personal data in this way.

#### General

The contents of this Privacy Policy may be changed at any time and User will be subject to terms as applicable at the time of usage.
